# Cody Carter



cody.carter@doubt.ai



+1 415-517-1114



https://i.doubt.ai

### Summary

With over a decade of experience working in Information Security and Loss Prevention, I have spent the past 5 years perfecting security program development for startups that need to achieve security goals while preserving the inherent value of being at a dynamic and flexible size. Meeting regulatory requirements efficiently, raising funds, reducing material risks, and responding to the needs of the business are the achievements that I place at the forefront of the programs I build.

I can work equally well with individual contributors and executives, I can absorb and live by your values, and I commit to protecting what is most important to your startup.

### **Experience**



#### **VOLUM** Security Manager & CISO

**Vouch Insurance** 

Jan 2022 - Present (7 months +)



### Staff Security Engineer

#### HomeLight

Jan 2021 - Present (1 year 7 months +)

Developed and implemented an Information Security Program that achieved Fundraising goals. Specific achievements included:

- Drafted key governance which included:
- Written Information Security Program
- Business Continuity Plan
- Incident Response Plan
- Crisis Communication Plan
- Risk Managment Policy (and supporting processes)
- Event Mangement Policy (and supporting processes)
- Acceptable Use Policy
- Data Security and Privacy Policy
- Implemented Event and Incident Management functions (in adherence with Sarbanes-Oxley) disclosure requirements)
- Implemented Risk Management function (in adherence with Sarbanes-Oxley reporting requirements)
- · Addressed GLBA requirements for Mortgage Lending (including Security Awareness Training and Phishing Simulation Testing)
- Implemented Vulnerability Management via Static Application Security Testing and Dynamic Application Security Testing.
- Developed Third-Party and Supply Chain Assurance capabilities (Due Diligence Questionnaire and Information Security Addendum requirements for Contracts)
- · Procured and Deployed Anti-Malware solution to company issued employee devices via JAMF (a Mobile Device Management suite for MAC) to comply with Cyber Insurance Policy requirements.

- Assisted the Partnership team in closing two high-priority B2B relationships that had been blocked previously due to security requirements.
- Developed Security Benchmarks for Google Workspaces and AWS.



#### Founding Consultant

Synoglyph Security Labs

Jan 2021 - Dec 2022 (2 years)

Provided security and privacy guidance to Pre-Seed and Seed funded startups.

#### Information Security Director

#### Forge

Oct 2019 - Jan 2021 (1 year 4 months)

- Built the initial Information Security Program, and lead the IT Teams for Forge Global, and Forge Trust (a subsidiary specializing in Asset Custody).
- Reported to the Board of Directors at Forge Global and Forge Trust regularly on Information Security issues.
- Developed and implemented an action plan in response to a Memorandum of Understanding addressing all regulatory concerns and restoring positive status with regulatory bodies.
- Developed and lead execution of the remote work strategy in response to the COVID-19 pandemic for Forge Trust, including:
- Provided supply-chain logistics for sourcing under-budget over 100 personal computing devices.
- Designing the remote architecture for securely accessing a traditional Mainframe.
- Developed and managed information security program requirements including:
- Event and Incident Management
- Information Security Governance (Policies and Processes)
- Risk Management
- Secure-by-Design and Secure Continuous Integration/Continuous Development
- Oversaw security, management, and migration planning of HP3000 Mainframe to virtualized system (cloud migration)

## Information Security Monitoring & Incident Response Manager

#### Funding Circle US

Sep 2018 - Oct 2019 (1 year 2 months)

- Lead deployment, signal tuning, quality assurance, documentation, and maintenance of detection and prevention tools
- Set the direction of automation & orchestration for processes developed to improve security operations
- Lead and manages a team of incident response analysts, engineers and marshaled resources to detect, investigate, and deploy counter-measures to mitigate information security risk (predominately risk associated with security events, control failures, policy violations, incidents and breaches)
- Coordinated with information security & general leadership to reduce regulatory, reputational and monetary risk associated with information security
- Enabled new business and reduces losses for existing business via information security practices

## **Senior Information Security Engineer**

Funding Circle US

Mar 2017 - Sep 2018 (1 year 7 months)

- Provided digital forensics and incident response for major incidents and breaches.
- Secured technically advanced tooling for new technologies (AWS, Kafka, Docker, infrastructure-ascode, Salesforce, Kubernetes/Mesos, Clojure programming language etc.)
- Advised on technically challenging secure architecture decisions (authentication/authorization, challenging logging & monitoring scenarios, digital forensics, automated security response etc.)

#### Security Software Engineer

Funding Circle US

Jul 2016 - Feb 2017 (8 months)

- Developed and implemented security controls, especially SPF, DKIM, DMARC, HIDS, LIDS, NIDS, Container Security, and Anti-Malware.
- Provided digital forensics and incident response for critical cases and events.
- Adapted and deployed open-source security tooling for commercial use (developing in Python, PERL, BASH etc.)

### Information Security Analyst

Castlight Health

Jun 2015 - Jul 2016 (1 year 2 months)

- Managed Vendor relationships on a variety of security tools, especially Web Application Firewalls (WAF), Security Indicent & Event Management (SIEM), Continuous Security Monitoring (CSM), Vulnerability Detection, and MSSP incident & event response.
- Developed and deployed a variety of security solutions, policies and processes.
- Participated in and passed SOC 2 audits, and maintained HIPAA and ISO 27001 standards.
- Prepared and distributed security reporting on events & incidents.

#### RSA AFCC Team Leader

RSA Security

Dec 2013 - May 2015 (1 year 6 months)

- Managed a cybercrime response team of 17 fraud prevention analysts.
- · Conducted training for all new analysts, ensuring they were ready to begin the tasks of an anti-fraud analyst
- Full responsibility for the professional qualification (and continued education) of new analysts from the first steps in the OTMS through the certified analyst.
- Managed the department recruiting evaluation center, conducting personal and technical interviews.
- · Advanced analysis of variant threads escalated from the AFCC, obfuscation, encoding, decoding, forensics investigations and credentials recovery.
- Managed the daily logistics of a fully-functioning office site (including addressing maintenance, IT, and scheduling).
- Assisted in growing the site from inception with 11 anti-fraud analysts to a profitable anti-fraud site with over 35 analysts performing advanced roles including Shift Managers, Follow Up, and Trojan investigators.

### RSA Anti-Fraud Command Center Analyst

RSA Security

Oct 2012 - Dec 2013 (1 year 3 months)

- Responsible for detecting and analyzing cyber-crimes (Phishing, Malware, Pharming, Brand Abuse, Fraudulent Emails, etc.).
- Taking prevention steps, terminating online frauds and performing computer forensic analysis.
- Comprehensive knowledge of website structures and related authorities (ISP's, Webhosting, Registrar, etc.)

#### **Education**



2007 - 2013



Cyber Security and Forensics 2014 - 2016

#### **Skills**

Information Security Program Management • Malware Analysis • Risk Management • Security Operations • Incident Response • Business Continuity Planning • Information Security Governance • Information Security Assurance and Due Dilligence • Application Security • Data Privacy